Register of the John F. Russell collection
Hoover Institution Archives
- United States Information Agency Issuances, 1950-1969 (Boxes 45-49)
  - 1950-1956 (Box-folder 45: 1)
  - 1958 (Box-folder 45: 2)
  - 1959 (Box-folder 45: 3-4)
  - 1960 (Box-folder 45: 5)
  - 1961 (Box-folder 45: 6)
  - 1962 (Box-folder 46: 1-3)
  - 1963 (Box-folder 46: 4-5)
  - 1964 (Box-folder 46: 1-4)
  - 1965 (Box-folder 48: 1-4)
  - 1966 (Box-folder 48: 5)
  - 1966 (cont'd.) (Box-folder 49: 1-2)
  - 1968 (Box-folder 49: 3)
  - 1969 (Box-folder 49: 4)
- United States Court Documents, 1949-1957 (Box 49)
  - Supreme Court and federal appellate and district court decisions, briefs and motions in cases involving communist issues (Box-folder 49: 5)
- University Course Bulletins, 1952-1968 (Box 50)
  - Course bulletins for various universities, notably the New School for Social Research (Box-folder 50: 1)
- Serial Issues, 1937-1966 (Boxes 50-54)
  - Communist Party, U.S.A. publications
    - General, 1935-1964 (Box-folder 50: 2)
    - Worker (Box-folder 50)
      - 1951-1954 (Box-folder 50: 3)
      - 1957 (Box-folder 50: 4)
      - 1957 (cont'd.) (Box-folder 51: 1)
      - 1958 (Box-folder 51: 2)
      - 1959 (Box-folder 51: 3)
  - Left-wing publications
    - General, 1945-1962 (Box-folder 52: 1)
    - I.F. Stone's Weekly, 1954-1957 (Box-folder 52: 2)
    - Militant (Socialist Workers Party), 1955-1956 (Box-folder 52: 3)
    - National Guardian, 1954-1959 (Box-folder 52: 4)
    - New Challenge, 1953-1956 (Box-folder 52: 5)
    - Sing Out!, 1953-1956 (Box-folder 52: 6)
  - Labor publications
    - March of Labor, 1953-1956 (Box-folder 52: 7)
    - UE News (United Electrical, Radio and Machine Workers of America), 1952-1957 (Box-folder 52: 8)
    - United Automobile Worker (United Automobile Workers Union), 1947-1956 (Box-folder 52: 9)
  - Religious publications
    - General, 1951-1960 (Box-folder 52: 10)
    - Catholic Worker, 1952-1962 (Box-folder 53: 1)
    - Christian Challenge (Episcopalian), 1965-1966 (Box-folder 53: 2)
    - Christian Register (Unitarian), 1955 (Box-folder 53: 3)
    - For God and Freedom, 1951-1955 (Box-folder 53: 4)
    - Mindszenty Report, 1966-1968 (Box-folder 53: 5)
    - Social Progress (Presbyterian), 1953-1954 (Box-folder 53: 6)
  - Jewish publications, 1952-1955 (Box-folder 53: 7)
  - Education publications, 1944-1958 (Box-folder 53: 8)
  - Anti-communist publications, 1950-1966 (Box-folder 54: 1)
  - Miscellaneous publications, 1937-1962 (Box-folder 54: 2)
- Pamphlets, 1920-1965 (Boxes 54-62)
  Arranged by issuing agency or topic.
  - American Bar Association (Box-folder 54: 3)
  - American Civil Liberties Union (Box-folder 54: 4)
  - American Committee for Cultural Freedom (Box-folder 54: 5)
  - American Friends Service Committee (Box-folder 54: 6)
  - American Legion (Box-folder 54: 7)
  - Americans for Democratic Action (Box-folder 54: 8)
  - Anti-communist publications (miscellaneous sources) (Box-folder 55: 1)
  - Basic Pamphlets (Corliss Lamont) (Box-folder 55: 2)
  - Chamber of Commerce of the United States (Box-folder 55: 3)
  - China (Chinese government publications) (Box-folder 55: 4)
  - Cinema Educational Guild (Myron C. Fagan) (Box-folder 55: 5)
  - Circuit Riders (Box-folder 56: 1)
  - Communist Party, U.S.A. (Box-folder 56: 2)
  - Communist Party, U.S.A. (cont'd.) (Box-folder 57: 1)
  - Communist Party-associated publications (miscellaneous Communist Party-associated sources) (Box-folder 57: 2)
  - Congress of Industrial Organizations (Box-folder 57: 3)
    Includes publications of individual unions.
  - Constitutional Educational League (Joseph P. Kamp) (Box-folder 58: 1)
  - Education (publications from miscellaneous sources about education) (Box-folder 58: 2)
  - Far East Reporter (Box-folder 58: 3)
  - Foreign countries (publications from miscellaneous sources about foreign countries) (Box-folder 58: 4)
  - Foreign countries (publications from miscellaneous sources about foreign countries) (cont'd.) (Box-folder 59: 1)
  - Foundation for Economic Education (Box-folder 59: 2)
  - General Motors Corporation ("Your Land and Mine" radio broadcast transcripts by Henry J. Taylor) (Box-folder 59: 3)
  - Harding College Freedom Forum (Box-folder 59: 4)
  - Institute of Fiscal and Political Education ("Democracy versus Communism" series) (Box-folder 59: 5)
  - Institute of Pacific Relations (Box-folder 59: 6)
  - Jewish publications (miscellaneous Jewish sources) (Box-folder 59: 7)
  - Left-wing publications (miscellaneous left-wing sources) (Box-folder 59: 8)
  - National Council for American Education (Box-folder 60: 1)
  - Public Affairs Pamphlets (Public Affairs Committee) (Box-folder 60: 2)
  - Religious publications (miscellaneous religious sources) (Box-folder 60: 3)
  - Socialist Labor Party (Box-folder 60: 4)
  - Soviet Union (Soviet government publications) (Box-folder 61: 1)
  - United Nations (publications from miscellaneous sources about the United Nations and world government) (Box-folder 61: 2)
  - United States, Department of State (Box-folder 61: 3)
  - United States government agencies (miscellaneous agencies) (Box-folder 61: 4)
  - United States domestic policy (publications from miscellaneous sources about domestic policy) (Box-folder 62: 1)
  - United States foreign policy (publications from miscellaneous sources about foreign policy) (Box-folder 62: 2)
  - Miscellaneous publications (Box-folder 62: 3)
- Audiovisual File, 1956-1966, undated (Boxes 62-63)
  Photographs, postcards, printed reproductions of drawings, and sound discs.
  - United States Information Agency-issued photographs and printed reproductions of drawings, 1956-1966 (Box-folder 62: 4)
    Relates to the Hungarian Revolution, American aid to South Vietnam, and Czechoslovak espionage in the United States.
  - East German-issued postcards of Paul Robeson, undated (Box-folder 62: 5)
  - Sound discs, undated (Box 63)
    - Songs of Free Men album featuring Paul Robeson
    - Songs of the Lincoln Brigade album
    - American Legion recording of speech by its national commander W. C. Daniel, "In Defense of the U.S. Immigration and Nationality Act"
- Declassified United States Government Records, 1959, undated (Box 62)
  Formerly security-classified records of the U.S. government, released in full or in part. Arranged chronologically by date of release by Hoover, thereunder chronologically by date of creation.
  - 2016 January release of records, 1959, undated (Box-folder 62: 6)
    Consists of a United States Information Agency, Office of Research and Analysis report, "Student Organizations in Colombia, 1958-1959" and an undated map, "Key Infiltrated Industries - Second Army Area."